When you finish this video, you will
have mastered confirmation entries,
which means you will be able to take
more winning trades, easily avoid a lot
of losses that would have otherwise
happened, increase the risk-to-reward
ratios on the trades that you do take,
meaning more profit per trade, and
ultimately create success in your
trading. We're not going to waste any
time at all. We want all of this for you
in your work. So, let's get straight
into it. This is what a standard
confirmation entry looks like. This one
is bullish. So, it's for buying
opportunities. The first thing we need
to see to create a confirmation entry is
a market that is downtrending, printing
lower lows and lower highs in price
consistently. Eventually, we see the
market break. We see a boss or a break
of structure. All this is is the market
changing from lower lows and lower highs
into higher highs. When a higher high
prints here, and this area needs to
include a closure, a candle closure, not
just wicks, by the way. This actually
validates a change in the trend. Now,
evidently with the trend being bearish,
a change in the trend turns the impulses
of the market into bullish impulses or
essentially means buyers have taken
control of this market and it is likely
to move up. Now, when we see this higher
high form, we then look for pullbacks
into areas of interest such as demand
zones. In fact, for every confirmation
entry, I use demand zones. We're going
to cover those on a real chart in just
one minute if you need more context on
that. And we will enter the trade from
the demand zone using a buy limit. So as
soon as this higher high is printed, we
can actually place a buy limit. Meaning
when the market hits this level, if it
moves to the upside, we'll then be
triggered automatically into a buy down
here and we'll profit from the movement
up. This is the highest probability way
to get into positions and provides the
best odds of profitability. So now let's
go over to a real chart and look at an
example. Here's an example of a
confirmation entry in a real market. So
here we have a market that is trending
to the downside initially. You can see
that the market is here creating
consistent lower lows and lower highs
showing that this is indeed a bearish
market or a downtrend. Now eventually
the market sees a break of structure
which takes place over this high. You
can see this is the final lower high in
the trend meaning essentially the final
point of which the market was trending
down. And after creating this low which
was a significant low we get this drive
to the upside which has broken through
the structure hence the BOS and created
a higher high. So this higher high here
is actually what forms the confirmation.
It shows us that the trend has shifted
from down to up. Now as we said we can
use demand zones to place our buy limit.
Now the demand zone in question is this
gray candle here. For me, I use the last
candle before the impulse. An impulse is
a strong bullish or bearish move. Here
we can see we have a strong bullish
movement. So, the last candle before
that is going to be this gray one, this
indecision candle, this kind of dogey
candle, or you could call it a pin bar,
whatever. It's a consolidation move
indicated by Wix before the large drive.
So, this is the last candle before the
impulse. That is what we use as our
demand. Now once this has formed and we
have a higher high as you can see we
have closures above here right? So these
candles have closed above the previous
high not just wicks. If we have just a
wick above this level the probability of
it actually leading into a successful
trade is slimmer because a wick shows
rejections. So if we'd have just created
wicks and then started trading down had
we bought here there'd be a higher
likelihood of us moving lower. But
because of these candlesticks closing
and obviously in this instance every one
of these candlesticks essentially being
bullish that shows us that buyers are
definitely in control of this market. So
using our theory of buying from demand
we could place a buy limit order just on
the demand level. Generally because of
spreads broker spreads I like to place
my entry just a little bit above even if
it's just 02 pips or so just to make
sure you do get tapped in if the
market's precise. Now for a confirmation
entry like this, one of the benefits we
get is we can put our stop loss just
directly underneath the low. The idea is
if the market comes back down to this
low. So if we were to see a drive to the
downside like this, the trade would be
invalidated. So we can put our stop loss
pretty much directly under that level
knowing that if the trade does come down
to this point, we'd rather just get out
of the trade and minimize the loss.
Obviously with confirmations though, we
are trading higher probability stuff
here. So these will work out and will
win a lot of the time. So with your
entry on the demand zone as a buy limit
order, an automatic buy if the market
returns to this level and a stop loss
underneath the significant low of the
confirmation entry, your target can then
go to wherever you want it to be. In
this instance, let's just put it towards
this supply zone. This would be a pretty
simple place for you to place your
target for a confirmation trade. Now,
we're going to click forward and we're
going to see how this trade plays out.
And you will see we come down, we get a
tap into that demand zone and then we
get a drive to the upside which in this
instance cleared our target. So the
confirmation actually took place
essentially between this area here.
Okay, we had a clear downtrend of lower
lows and lower highs. We had a break of
structure driving to the upside and
creating a higher high. Then we have a
pullback to the natural demand zone
which is the candle that created this
impulsive move. the last candle before
the impulse. When the market taps this
level, we then see a drive to the upside
which carries us through towards the
target that we had set for the position.
Now, why do we use demand for entries?
Well, a demand zone simply shows us if
we think about what this actually
indicates, an area where significant
buying has taken place in the past. In
this instance as well, very fresh
significant buying. buying that's
actually created the shift in the trend
that we're looking at just here. This
buying therefore coming from this level
tells us that this level of demand, this
area, this zone is seen as a discounted
price to buy from or a good price to
purchase this asset, whatever asset it
may be. The idea is then if the market
is able to return to this natural buying
level, this discounted price level, new
traders or the same traders who bought
here will be looking to buy once again
because it is a fair price to pay for
this asset. So when the market returns
to this level, we see the momentum slow
down, market taps demand, our buy limit
is triggered and then we see this big
drive to the upside. So that is why we
look to buy from demand in the case of a
bullish reversal. Now I just want to
explain everything works exactly the
same for bearish positions except we are
of course looking for shifts from higher
highs and higher lows into lower lows
and lower highs. So when the market
stops forming these higher highs and
instead creates an impulse that drives
into a lower low, we then form our
bearish confirmation because the higher
lows have broken, a lower low has formed
and we can now see that sellers are in
control. So the most probable movement
from here is to sell from what we would
call then a supply zone which is once
again just the last candle before the
impulse and in this instance is seen as
a premium price to sell an asset. The
supply zone is going to be marked just
like a demand zone would but it's the
other way round. And when that supply
zone is met, it will trigger a sell
limit order that we place on or just
below that level. Our sell limit order
will be triggered. Our stop loss will be
above the swing high. And in this
instance, if we do run nicely, we will
get a very solid entry for our position
with very positive risk-to-reward. And
if the market runs against us, we'll be
stopped out quickly. We can minimize the
loss and move on to the next trade. So,
they work exactly the same for bearish
scenarios, except everything is
essentially flipped on its head.
Confirmation entries like the one we
just looked at are best used in context
as well. Now in this example we can see
this is a clearly larger uptrending
market forming these higher highs and
higher lows. We had a break of structure
on a high time frame showing us this
market is bullish and then the actual
confirmation entry which took place here
came from an area of demand. You can see
just here. So here we benefit from kind
of top- down analysis or high time frame
and low time frame agreement. The high
time frame, of course, as we've just
covered, is pointing to the upside. And
then what we're doing is looking inside
of the pullback move, tracking the lower
lows and lower highs that this pullback
is forming. And when these lower lows
and lower highs shift into higher highs
from this area of demand that we've just
discussed, this shows us that the low
time frame being this that we're looking
at here agrees with the high time frame.
Okay? High time frame trend being this
uptrend. low time frame trend being the
downtrend here shifting into the
uptrend. This context gives us an
understanding that we are trading not
just in the right direction on this
smaller piece of price action but also
in the right direction on this larger
piece of price action as well. So let's
take a look at some more examples of
confirmations in context. So there are
two points of which confirmation entries
can take place from. Number one is a
reversal and that's what we're about to
look at here. Number two is a
continuation which will follow on from
this position. So if we take a look at
this, what we've seen is a downtrending
market here. Uh lower high was crafted
here and then the market has pushed up
and broken through the structure. Okay.
So from a confirmation entry
perspective, we're starting to see what
we want to see. We have the validation
up here, a closure creating a higher
high, which means we could now use our
imbalanced demand to place a buy limit.
Now, taking a look through this trend,
we see we still have the demand zone
that really started to create the first
bullish movements. It's going to be this
last candle before the impulse. Okay,
small candle before a large rally away.
And this candle is still not yet
retested. So, our buy limit, as we've
said, can go just on or just above this
zone. Our stop loss can go just
underneath the confirmation. Our stop
loss can go just underneath the swing
low of this confirmation entry. and our
target will just run it to the actual
swing high. Now, when you're taking
reversal trades like this, and the
reason that this one is a reversal
trade, by the way, is that it doesn't
really come from any significant areas,
right? We're looking at a straight shift
from downtrend into uptrend. And we
don't have that same context that we had
in NZD/USD, for example, where this is
coming from a demand zone. If we take a
look to the left, we see some
significant swing lows, and one of them
is going to be just here. Another one is
going to be just here. You'll see that
the market swept through one of them and
then made this run away. So, we don't
really have significant uptrend on this
larger perspective. And we also don't
really have a significant demand zone or
anything that this reaction is coming
from. We had a small sweep of liquidity,
but nothing really significant. So, what
we're looking at here is pretty much a
direct reversal. Okay? We're looking at
the end of a downtrend, the start of an
uptrend. we don't have that same context
in terms of this being a demand zone
retest or anything like that. So for a
reversal trade like this, we can
actually look to take the targets much
higher because what we're doing here is
getting into the start of a new trend.
So for the sake of this, let's just set
the target to a previous swing high.
This downtrend turning into an uptrend.
Let's just use this swing high for
example sake. We could realistically if
we expected this market was going to
reverse a lot further target potentially
even the notable highs but let's work
with this for now. So this is a reversal
confirmation entry. We have our
structural downtrend here. Okay. Then we
have a break of structure creating our
structural uptrend. Now we are placing a
buy limit ready to capitalize on a
movement like this or a reversal in the
trend. And we're looking to catch the
very start of this trending move. So
let's let this market run forward.
You'll see from this we get a run down,
a very nice precise tap in to the area
of demand and then we go and run all the
way up to the targets and continue
trading even higher. So that is a
reversal confirmation entry. We just
simply saw the market changing from
lower lows and lower highs into higher
highs and higher lows down here. We
didn't really get the significant uh
context we'd want for a kind of
continuation trade because we are just
looking at a direct change from down to
up. Okay. Now, you don't only have to
trade confirmations at reversals in the
market. If a market has already shifted
like this one, which is now moving
bullish, we can use confirmation entries
much like the example on NZD CAD to take
continuation trades in line with this
bigger trend. Okay. So, if we run this
market forward, we have a pretty
significant drive to the upside here.
There's a few areas the market could
reverse from. We're always going to be
looking for continuations at demand
zones. So, some of the demand zones I'm
looking at here, these last candles
before the impulse. As you can see, this
instance here, we have final candle
impulse away. Then, we have an uh
indecision candle and then another push
away. So, these are some areas we could
look at if the market was to come into
them. Generally then what we would want
to see would be that lower time frame or
smaller trend being right now the
existing trend that's crafting at this
point in time. And if we started to see
this shifting like so we could then buy
limit to continue taking the market
higher. Now the difference between this
one and the one we've just looked at is
this one is coming from the end of a
downtrend. So we're seeing a downtrend
end and a new uptrend form. This second
trade we already have the uptrend
formed. we already have the movements
being uh in motion essentially. So what
we'd be looking for is just a simple way
to join this trend as it already moves.
Okay. So let's run this market forward a
little bit and see how things get on. We
see the market coming down towards one
of those potential demand zones. At the
moment we haven't really seen anything
significant here, right? Why? Because
this is our low. We haven't yet created
a lower low and then pushed up into a
higher high. So this for now can just be
seen as a consolidation. We would
ideally want to see the market coming
down and creating a change in the trend
and creating a new low before we then
started to see a change in the trend.
All right. So here we're starting to see
something interesting. We've actually
seen at this point the market come down
and trade into this area of demand. So
this is going to be our pretty much
significant low. We could look at this
kind of structure point. perhaps the
previous structure point as well for
some potential levels to break. All
right. Now, why would we not classify
this as a break to the upside? Well, as
we said, this is just wicks. Wicks show
rejections. So, this movement from here
like so can't be seen as a confirmation
entry at this point. Meaning buys
wouldn't really be good from there
because we haven't had confirmed change
in the trend. We just had rejections.
Yes, the market did attempt to go
higher, but sellers have pushed it back
down. So, realistically, we do need to
start seeing some of these highs taken
out to confirm our change in the trend.
Now, at this point in time, we've seen a
rally. This rally after retesting the
demand zone down here, which refined to
the 30 minute, could be pulled into this
indecision candle. This rally has
actually broken through a couple of
structure points. So, we have this
structure point broken. We have this
structure point, this one as well. And
we even actually do have closures above
some of these significant higher levels
as well. So with this said, we now have,
and let's use this level to mark it out,
our BOS or break structure where the
market has changed from bearish now into
bullish. What we can do at this point is
find our demand zone and place our buy
limit. Okay. So, following the same
rule, I'm sure you can see where this
demand zone is going to be. We are
looking for the last candle before the
impulse. A consolidation candle, large
wiki candle essentially before the
drives away. That's going to be this
blue candle here for me. So, that is my
last candle before the impulse for this
trade. Realistically, I don't think we
need to go all the way down here with
our stop. The shift has happened at this
point. So, we can just put the stop loss
underneath either the notable swing low,
which is going to be just these wicks,
or if we wanted to be a little bit more
aggressive, we could go under this
demand. Now, this trade for me, I think
a good place to put the stop would
simply be here. If we think the market
is going to get this low, it is then
likely to continue going even lower. So,
it would make more sense to just get out
of the trade, call it quits, and take
the loss, small controlled loss, rather
than let that get out of hand. Because
we're in a continuation of an uptrending
move, we can just target as a very
simple target the swing high. Okay? Now,
if you really wanted to as well, as you
can see, you could hold those initial
trades for longer when you do get those
reversal positions, but this would have
been a very healthy profit regardless,
even if you'd only taken the market to
this level. So there is no harm with
this one and this is just a great way to
join in the trends when they are then
once again reversing and continuing back
in the larger direction. So this is what
we call an impulse move and this is what
we call a corrective move. Okay, what
we're looking for here is just a simple
continuation of a new impulse move to
take us into new highs in this trend.
And this is how we would essentially set
the trade up to get into it. So now if
we allow the market to play forward, we
see a little bit of consolidation.
Market comes down towards that demand
and then we see a nice strong impulse
away. Now an interesting thing to note
here as well is just how strong this
bullish move is compared to the bearish
moves that we've seen. And this is how
we know we're on the right side of the
market. And this is really what we're
looking for when we take these
continuation trades. You can see that
the impulse that started the uptrend
from our initial entry all the way up
here was very fast and strong. There
wasn't really any pullbacks. Okay, we
didn't really get any slowdowns in the
price action. It was just a fast, clear,
strong move all the way up. The
corrective move was actually then pretty
slow. Okay, we didn't really do much. We
just moved down very slowly. We still
kept seeing attempts to go higher from
buyers. And then of course when we tap
into that significant area and we start
to see some of those structural points
shifting that creates strength from the
buyers, you can see how strong this
bullish move is. And then of course when
we get our tap in triggering our buy
limit, we see a new very strong move
again. So we know we're on the right
side of the market here and trading with
the real direction of the real trend. So
those are the two different places to
use confirmation entries in context. We
have number one, the reversal trade
where we are simply looking for a
downtrend ending. When the downtrend
ends, we can then take a position into a
new uptrend. A continuation trade will
take place when a trend is already
existing. In this instance, we see that
this is a clear uptrend and all we're
looking to do is use that confirmation
pattern to join in to an existing
uptrend. Now, I think both are as good
as each other. you are going to be able
to capitalize more on the full reversal
trades because you're getting in sooner.
You're getting in right at the start of
a trend. But these continuation trades
can be very high probability because
you're already moving in line with a
market that is showing clear strength
from buyers or sellers. Okay. Now, of
course, as we've said as well, these
could go both ways. We could have been
looking at an uptrend, shifting into a
downtrend for our reversal trade up
here. And then we could have been
looking for a continuation of lower
price action once the market started
breaking lower to get us into a position
to trade to the downside in line with
the existing trend. That's why we call
it a continuation. Regardless, the entry
model is pretty much exactly the same.
The context of which they occur is the
only thing that is slightly different.
So that is how we use confirmation
entries in different contexts. Now, if
you want to learn how I got these
results in 2024 and how my students get
results like this pretty much every
single week that goes by, then head over
to the link in the description and you
can join my free trading course. It's a
seven-part video series which is going
to help you to build a system, simplify
trading, improve your trades, and find
success. The link is at the top of the
description for this. It's 100% free and
I will also send you lessons, some of my
best lessons via email for as long as
you want me to. I highly recommend you
do this. It's going to change the game
for you. But if you don't want to do
that, make sure you watch this video
next because this is going to provide
you a lot of value as well. So, thank
you for watching. I hope you've enjoyed
this class. Go out there and back test
your confirmation entries.